你不该玩的 女人
Shouldn't have played, lady.
这不是你的游戏
Not your game.
搞什么鬼
What the shit?
不 真的 告诉我 搞什么鬼
No, really, just tell me … what the shit?!
《行尸走肉》
逃跑者可能在去救世堂的路上
The escapees could be en route to the Sanctuary.
亨利要找他们 而我们要找亨利
They are Henry's quarry and Henry, ours.
这里可能还会被袭击 玛姬需要我留下
There could be another attack. Maggie needs me here.
你可以走
You can leave.
但你选择不走
But you choose not to.
告诉我原因
Tell me why.
你走吧
Just go.
你觉得他已经死了
You think he's already dead.
你相信这点吗
Is that what you believe?
还是你无法允许自己相信他没死
Or can you not allow yourself to believe otherwise?
是你告诉我要假装成真
You told me to pretend to make it real.
直到真的成真 而你却做不到
until it is so, and you cannot.
假装也未必会成真
It may not be so.
我为亨利担心
I fear for Henry.
我以为你是我见过的最勇敢的人
You, who I thought were the bravest person I've met…
不
No.
你
You…
懦弱阻拦了你
You're stopped by cowardice.
已经一天多了
It's been over a day.
还是没生病 医生说我没事了
Still not sick. Doc says I'm cool.
你真他妈坚强
You're a tough son of a bitch.
达里尔
Daryl,
这意味着德怀特用干净的箭头射中了我
it just means that Dwight shot me with a clean arrow.
或者是你运气好 什么都有可能
Or it means you got lucky. Could be anything.
这不是咬伤 有时候不会出事
It's not like a bite. Sometimes nothing happens.
- 达里尔 - 听着 如果德怀特知道这事
- Daryl… - Look, if Dwight knew,
他本可以警告我们 给我们发消息
could've warned us, could've sent us a message.
也许他无法那样做
Well, maybe he couldn't.
他浪费了一整天的时间 而我们的人躺在地上死去
He let a whole day go by while our people lay around dying.
战斗中受伤的其他人全都生病了
Everybody else in the battle who got injured got sick.
这不可能是意外
That can't be an accident.
所以他就可以脱罪了 是这样吗
So he just gets a pass? Is that it?
也许是
Maybe.
你说过我们也许需要他
Look, you said that we might need him,
我们现在也许最需要他
and we might need him now more than ever,
我的意思是 如果我杀了他
and what I'm saying is that if I had killed him,
也许我现在就死了
maybe I would be dead right now.
听着 你想做什么随你
Look, do what you gotta do.
但要知道你只是为了自己
But know it's just for you.
我退出了
I'm out.
你
Do you…
你想看吗
Do you want to read it?
你要出去了
You're going out there.
我们需要食物
We need food.
我要去找食物
I'm gonna find some.
他给你写了什么
What did he write you?
我不知道 我没法看
I don't know. I-I can't.
- 等等 - 我做不到
- Wait. - I can't.
你必须看
You have to.
我也这样做过
I did it, too…
当我遇上这种事的时候
when it happened to me.
你一直在四处逃避
You keep moving to move away from it.
安德莉亚拦住了我
Andrea stopped me.
现在 我要拦住你
And now… I'm stopping you.
卡尔写了信 是因为他想让你看
Carl wrote that because he wanted you to read it.
这是他做的最后一件事
It was one of the last things he ever did.
你要留下
You're stayin'.
爸爸
你要去找他吗
You goin' lookin' for him?
找他们
For them.
- 你不必这么做的 摩根 - 我必须做
- You don't have to, Morgan. - I do.
我之前可以做 也应该做
I could've before, and I should've.
我本来就该做
I was supposed to.
瞧 我们是一样的 我本来就该做
See, we're the same, and I was supposed to.
而我以为…
And I thought that…
以为我必须做
Thought I had to.
以为会有不同
Thought it'd be different.
摩根
Morgan.
好吧
Fine.
但我和你一起去
But I'm coming with you.
接力车都就位了
The relay cars are in position.
如果救世军杀回来
If the Saviors are coming back,
我们有十到十五分钟做准备
we'll have 10, maybe 15 minutes heads-up.
- 弹药呢 - 和我们估算的差不多
- And our ammo? - 'Bout what we thought.
无法再抵御一次这种规模的袭击了
Not enough to fend off another attack of that size.
也许我们不用担心这个
‭Well, maybe we don't gotta worry about that no more.
至少现在不用了
At least for now.
也许我们只能肉搏了
Maybe going hand-to-hand's our only option.
你觉得他们的弹药也不多了吗
You think they're low on ammo?
他们在穿过救世堂的尸群时
Well, they must've gone through a whole bunch of it.
肯定用掉了很多弹药
getting through them walkers at Sanctuary.
再加上也没多少地方能补充弹药
And there's not a lot of places to find more.
该死的
Mierda.
他们手上有我们的子弹制造者 他们可以造
They have our bullet maker. They can make more.
你觉得救世军有造子弹的原料和设备吗
You think the Saviors have what he'd need to make them?
就算没有 我也知道他们能在哪里找到
If they don't, ‭I know where they'd find it.
我闻到了
I smell it.
不管这里发生过什么 我都闻到了
Whatever the holy hell happened here, I smell it.
生火就是为了这个 还有那些盐 放火除味
That's what that fire is about, that salt, burning it away.
我告诉过你了 人是资源
I told you, people are a resource.
我可不会把这种资源抛开
I don't throw resources like that away.
我非常有信心
I got a lot of confidence.
大部分人都可以走上正路…
that most people can be put on the right path …
我那条路
my path.
我是不会把你的人杀光的
I wouldn't have killed all your people.
不会
No.
那是某个不按计划行事的人干的
That was the work of someone not following the program.
但这个
But this?
这个是我的失误
This is my mistake.
我认了
I'll own this.
我给了某个人一次机会
I took a chance on someone,
想着那么做是正确的
thought I was doing the right thing,
但这一切都不过是打了我自己的脸
and all I did ‭was punch myself in the dick.
我对此很抱歉
I am sorry for this.
真心的
I really am.
很抱歉你失去了一切
I'm sorry that you lost all you had.
但我知道 我可以以某种方式帮你夺回一切
But I know, in some way, I can help get it back,
我们…
that we …
这是我们最靠谱的猜测 他们很有可能
This is our best bet. It'd make sense.
会待在来时走的路附近
they'd stay near the road they'd take to get there.
有一半的可能性他们会…
50/50 chance they'd be…
是什么
What is it?
萝卜
Turnip.
他们之前走过这里
They were on this side of the road.
亨利
Henry.
Henry!
亨利
Henry.
你知道是什么
You know what it is.
你本该知道的
You were supposed to.
你不在这里 他不在这里
You're not here. He's not here.
你不在这里
You are not here!
你不该在那
You weren't supposed to be there.
不该 不该
You weren't. You were…
他死了 你知道的
He's dead. You know he is.
我不是来找他的
I didn't come out here to look for him.
我是来看好你的
I came out here to keep an eye on you.
是啊 我看过
Yeah, I've seen it.
你救人 我已经看过很多次了
You save people. ‭I've seen it again and again.
但你救不了死人 卡萝尔
But you can't save the dead, Carol.
你没有死
You're not dead.
我知道 不是我 我不会死
I know. Not me. I don't die.
我只是会看到死
I just see it.
无休无止
Again and again.
没完没了
就算我看向别处 还是能看到
And even when I look away, still see it.
穿过这里
Came through here.
可能是条近路
Probably a shortcut.
直通前面的公路
Straight line to the road ahead.
他们去哪了
Where'd they go?
- 我们已经告诉过玛姬… - 也告诉我一遍
- We already told Maggie every… - So, tell me.
最有可能是救世堂
Sanctuary's our best guess.
基本是唯一的可能
It's pretty much our only guess.
他们讨论过该怎么逃
There'd been some talk about trying to get out,
但只是说说而已 没什么特别的
but it was just talk, nothin' specific.
以为他们有计划是高看了他们
Thinkin' they had a plan's giving 'em too much credit.
他们只是看到机会就逃了出去
They saw an opening, and they took it.
换做是你 你会怎么回去
What if it was you? How'd you get back there?
你只能步行 可能还有队友受伤
You're on foot, there's probably someone injured.
也许你需要一个藏身处并且想点办法
Maybe you need a place to hole up and figure things out.
距山边大路三英里的地方有个老酒吧
There's an old dive bar three miles off Edgehill Parkway.
他们有人带我去过一次
Some of them, uh, took me there once.
他们需要我给些专业意见
They wanted my expert opinion on what it'd take.
如何把那地方改造成哨站
to turn the place into an outpost.
位置就在两地之间
It's between here and there,
但他们去那里的可能性…
but the chances they'd actually g…
我不知道这算不算有价值的线索
I don't know if this is any kind of a lead,
但如果你要去那里…
but if you're going out there…
这请求可能有些过分 你能否帮我个忙
it's not for nothing…can you do me a favor?
如果你真找到了他们
If you happen to find them…
请不要杀那些没必要杀的人
…don't kill any more of them than you have to.
昨晚出事以后 他们做了选择
When it went bad last night, they…they made a choice.
是个错误的选择
It was the wrong choice.
他们有些人可能还没醒悟
Some of them, ‭probably hasn't hit 'em yet.
你可以点醒他们 通过带他们回来
You could show 'em…by bringin' 'em back.
你可以做到的
You could do that.
对 我可以
Yeah, I could.
咱们谈谈
Hey! Let's talk about this!
这事与我无关
I had nothing to do with this!
我拿到你的照明棒了
I got your flare.
就是你想用来点火烧我宝贝的那根
for that little fire you were gonna start with my girl.
告诉你 开枪打这位
And let me tell you, I pulled my punch.
烧伤先生时 我可是留了一手
Tried to hit old Mr. Ninety-Degrees there.
不管你在做什么
Look, whatever you're doing…
你一定不是真想这么做
you must not really want to do it.
因为如果你真想的话
'Cause if you did,
就不会让我在这坐拥一大箱武器
you wouldn't have left me sitting here with a bag full of guns.
我在箱子里还找到了一些东西
Found something else in there, too.
你一定很珍视这些照片
Gotta think these snaps are near and dear.
所以我们来聊聊吧
So let's have a chat.
来治疗创伤吧
Let the healing begin.
我们应该等等
We should wait.
让尸群过去
Let it pass.
踪迹径直穿了过去
Trail goes straight through.
有可能跟丢的
We could lose it.
有可能丢的不只是踪迹
We could lose more than the trail.
摩根
Morgan.
那根棍子
That stick.
是亨利的
It's Henry's.
摩根 停下
Morgan, stop.
它是从另一条路来的
It came from the other road.
我们走那边 或许会找到他
We go that way, maybe … maybe we can find him.
我们走那条路 你知道我们会找到什么
We take that road, you know what we'll find.
但我不知道
But I don't.
我只是觉得会那样
I decided … ‭I decided what It would be.
但我无法确定 除非我去了
But I won't know unless I go…
除非我试过
unless I try.
你也可以试试
And you can try, too.
不
No.
不 我不能
No, I can't. I…
你救人
You save people.
我看别人死
I watch 'em die.
我必须这样
I have to.
我应该这样
I'm supposed to.
我试图跑的时候 你找到了我
When I tried to run, you found me.
你救了我
You saved me.
你知道我能回头
You knew I could come back.
你也可以的
And you can, too.
那不是我
That wasn't me.
我没你那么坚强
I'm not strong like you.
我一直在那里 看着他们
I was there that whole time, watchin' 'em,
知道会发生不好的事
knowin' that something would happen.
我知道的 我预见到了
I knew it. I saw it.
我在等着坏事发生 然后发生了 总是…
I was waiting for it to happen, and then it did, like it…
总是会发生
Like it always does.
所以我必须这样
So I just have to.
我必须杀了他们
I have to kill 'em.
我必须杀
I have to.
摩根
Morgan…
Morgan.
别动那些照片
Leave those pictures alone.
我就想着它们对你有所意义
I figured they meant something to you.
尤其还是绝版 对吗
Especially considering this is it, right?
毕竟不是说打印就能打印
I mean, it's not like you can just pop around the corner and order yourself some prints.
我再问你一次
So I'm gonna ask you one more time.
搞什么鬼
What the shit?
你是这样杀人的吗
I mean, this … this is how you kill people?
用那玩意
With that thing?
缓慢地
Slowly?
不是
No.
人是资源
People are a resource.
把照明棒拿开 求你了
Move the flare away … please.
那是我仅有的东西
They're all I have left.
那是这地方仅有的东西
They're all this place has left.
你夺走了我的世界 我的一切
You took my world, everything.
你夺走了我
You took away me.
我妻子叫露西尔
My wife's name was Lucille.
她帮我坚持了下来
She got me through.
我屁都没给她 但她帮我坚持了下来
I didn't give her shit, and she got me through.
那只是生活
Just life.
普通的生活
Regular life.
球棒 帮我在末世坚持了下来
The bat … The bat got me through this.
所以我以她命名它
So I named it after her.
就这样 除此之外跟她没有更多关系
That's it. Nothing more to do with her than that.
但那是我仅剩的她的最后一部分
But it is the last little piece of her that I got left.
有点像这些照片对你的意义 对吧
Sort of like these snaps for you, huh?
是的
Yes.
住手吧
Just stop.
什么鬼
What the shit?
不不不
No! No! No!
我在这 我在这
I'm here! I'm here!
我在这
I'm here!
I'm here.
不 别
No. No, don't!
别
Don't!
我没烧掉你的照片
I-I didn't burn your pictures.
我没那么做 我不会做的
I didn't do it. I wouldn't.
那是我对她仅剩的念想
That is all I have left of her.
你烧了球棒 你只会得到灰烬
You burn her, ‭and all you have is ashes.
不 我能伤到你
No, I get to hurt you.
我没那么做
I didn't do it.
我能解决此事
I can settle it.
我以蛋蛋担保 我会的
I swear on my sack, I will.
我能解决此事
I can settle it.
好吗
Okay?
摩根
Morgan.
摩根 摩根
Morgan. Morgan, hey.
你认识我
You know me.
我…
I…
我不对劲
I'm not right.
也许你不应该出来
Maybe … Maybe you shouldn't be out …
我哪都不会去
Hey, I'm not going anywhere.
你出来是为了找他们
You're out here for them.
我也是
Me, too.
我们杀了他们 你和我
Then, we finish it, you and me.
我们当时得离开大路 离开树林 但仍然…
We had to get off the road, out of the forest, and still…
也许我们处理得不够及时
Maybe we didn't do it in time.
对 但也许够及时
Yeah, but maybe we did.
他们看起来没精神
Maybe they don't look so hot.
可能是因为被截肢了
'cause we hacked off part of them.
我们不能把他们丢在这
We're not just gonna leave them here.
看看他们 他们跟死没两样了
Look at them. They're dead already.
他说得对
He's right.
他们知道规矩
They knew the rules.
自己搞砸了 不会有人帮你
You pooch it, nobody carries you.
即使我们一起经历了这么多吗
After everything we've been through?
- 现在很乱 我们别… - 我们定下规矩
- Things are shaky, man. Let's not … - Look, we got the rules.
是为了让受伤的人不累及其他同伴
so somebody goin' down don't take the rest of us with them.
这就是个好例子
Case in point.
要不是因为他们 我们都快到家了
We could've been halfway home by now.
我昏迷多久了
How long was I out?
久到让你来到这里
Just long enough to end up here.
就算我们回去了 之后呢
Say we make it. Huh? What then?
他说得对 杰瑞德
He's right, Jared.
那里有什么值得我们回去
What do we got waiting for us back there?
要不我们自己走吧 跟救世军一刀两断
Maybe we go our own way, be done with the Saviors.
我们闯祸了 西蒙可没打算救我们
We pooched it. Simon wasn't gonna carry us.
没错 因为我们输了
That's right. Because we lost.
但现在情况不一样了
But things have changed.
把混蛋瑞克交给尼根是场胜利
Delivering Rick the Prick to Negan is a win.
我们自己收拾好了这个烂摊子
We wiped our own asses on this one,
老大会赏识我们的
and the Big Man is gonna recognize.
他醒了
Hey. He's awake.
起床啦 卷毛
Rise and shine, curly.
准备好走路了吗
You ready to do some walkin'?
没错
Yeah.
你当然准备好了
Of course you are.
收拾东西 伙计们
Pack it up, boys!
我们把累赘都扔掉 继续前进
We're ditchin' the dead weight and movin' on.
不过是例行减负 就这样
This is a loose-end sort of thing, that's it.
对你们和我们都更好
It's gonna be better for you, better for us.
等等 我的卡车离得不远
Wait! My truck's not far.
我们可以送他们去山顶寨看医生
We can get 'em to the Hilltop's doctor.
他们可以跟我们回去
They could come back with us.
你们都可以
You all could.
你们不想要这样的
You didn't want this.
你们临时做了错误选择
You made a split-second choice, and you chose wrong,
但还为时不晚
but it's not too late.
给我们松绑 配合我们
You cut us loose, you cooperate…
我们就让你们重头再来
we'll give you a fresh start.
给你们融入我们社区的机会
A chance to become part of our community,
成为我们中的一员
to become one of us.
我向你们做出了承诺
I'm giving you my word.
如今没多少有意义的东西
There's not a lot ‭that's worth much these days,
但一个男人的承诺
but a man's word…
应该是有所意义的 对吧
that's gotta mean somethin', right?
你们这些蠢货不会真蠢到相信他吧
You asshats aren't dumb enough to believe that.
让他说完 我们可以商量一下
We can hear him out. W-We could talk it over.
实际上 没有时间了
Thing is, there isn't time for that.
有尸群在附近 可能正冲着我们来了
There's a herd out there, close, probably headed this way.
你们都需要做出选择
You're all gonna need to make a choice,
现在就要做
and it's gonna have to be now.
醒醒吧 大家
Wake up, everybody!
没有什么尸群
There isn't any herd.
山顶寨没有什么「约定」等着我们
There isn't any "deal" waiting back at Hilltop.
你们以为这俩混球是来救我们的吗
You think these asswipes came here to save us?
他们是来杀人的
They came here for blood.
妈的 这家伙亲手掐死了
Hell, this one strangled one of his own guys to death.
他们一个自己人
with his own hands.
瑞克说的都是扯淡
All Rick is saying here is a steaming pile of bullshit.
你说对了
You know, you're right.
我来这是为了做我该做的事
I came here to do what I was supposed to.
杀光你们剩下的所有人
To kill every last one of you.
省省子弹吧 你们会需要的
You should save your bullets, 'cause you're gonna need 'em.
尸群就要来了
That herd, it is comin'.
它们也许会听到呻吟和咳嗽声
Maybe they'll hear the moans or the coughs, you know?
它们也许会从缺口误打误撞闯进来
Maybe they'll just stumble in through the open walls,
但是它们要来了
but they are comin'.
然后接下来
And then after …
当你们只剩下皮囊
after, when you're just torn skin.
碎牙和血滩…
and loose teeth and blood…
当你们只不过是它们没吃掉的残渣时
when you're nothing but the stuff that they didn't eat…
那就真他妈可惜了
…well, that'll be a damn shame.
因为没留下什么人等我来杀了
Because there won't be a single one of you left for me to kill.
说完了
We're done.
我们丢下他们走吧
Let's dump 'em and bounce.
我想吃三明治了
I want a sandwich.
看到了吗 一切都没变
See? It doesn't change.
永远不变
It never changes.
我不会死
And I don't die.
我不会 没人会死
I don't. Nobody dies!
因为大家都会变
'Cause everybody turns!
大家都会变
Hey! Everybody turns!
你在做什么
Hey. What are you doing?
你会毁了我们回山顶寨的机会
You'll ruin our chances of getting back to Hilltop.
有行尸 我们被包围了
Walkers! We're surrounded!
实际上 我们已经杀死你们了
Thing is, we've already killed you.
它们进来了 进来了
Some coming in! Some coming in!
光靠你们挡不住尸群
You're too weak to take on this herd alone.
给我们松绑
Cut us loose.
给我们武器 我们能帮你们
Give us our weapons. We can help you!
不 谁都不准松绑
No! Nobody's cutting anybody loose!
我现在就杀了这俩混蛋
I'm killing these pricks right now.
快点
Come on!
不
No!
- 快点 - 我们必须找条路出去
- Come on! - We gotta find a way out!
棍子给我
Hey, give me the stick!
我们快没子弹了 你上
We're almost out. Go on ahead.
狗杂种
Son of a bitch!
你不是喜欢棍子吗
You like sticks, right?
松手 松手
Let go! Let go!
松手 不不 松手
Let go! No, no! Let go!
松手
Let go!
Aah! Let go!
松手
Let go!
Let go.
你说过…
You said…
- 你说过… - 我说谎了
- You said … - I lied.
我没说谎
I … I didn't.
我们本可以…
We could've …
我们之后…本可以一起活下去
We could've lived… after.
在这之后
After this.
所有人都会变
Everybody turns.
你救了我
You saved me.
摩根 你救了我
Morgan, you saved me.
我本来会死的
I would've died.
也许就在那条街上 在你屋前
Maybe on that street, right in front of your house.
你不认识我
You didn't know me.
你为什么要那样做
Why'd you do it?
我们该走了
We should go.
告诉我
Just tell me.
你为什么救我
Why'd you save me?
- 你儿子当时在那里 - 不
- You had your son there. … No.
- 是的 - 不
- You did. - Hey, no.
你为什么救我 为什么
Why'd you save me? Why?
因为
Because.
因…
Be…
因为我儿子当时在那里
Because my son was there.
你没有失去你自己
You didn't lose you.
你应该知道这点
You should know that.
你想告诉我刚才他妈发生了什么吗
Now, you wanna tell me what the hell happened here?
那是怎么回事
What that was all about?
你可以和我一起走
You can come with me, you know.
走新的道路
Follow a new path.
你的道路吗
Your path?
提议长期有效
The offer stands.
我会偶尔来看看
I'll swing by again sometime.
谁知道呢
Who knows?
说不定以后你会想分享呢
Maybe you'll want to share.
救救我
Help me!
求求了
Please!
救救我 救救我
Help me! Help me!
对不起
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
真对不起
I'm so, so sorry.
我错了
I was wrong.
你可以活下来的
You could survive.
我错了
I was wrong.
这就办
On it.
过来 这边
Hey! Come here! Right here!
引开行尸
Yo! Distract the deadies!
对 过来
That's it! Come right here!
这边 这边
Over here! Over here! Hey!
陛下
Your Majesty!
哥们
Dude.
以西结
Ezekiel!
你说得对 我很怕
You were right. I was afraid.
是的 你是很怕 我看到了
Oh, yeah, you were. I saw it.
但你不懦弱
But you are no coward.
我曾有过一个女儿
I had a daughter.
在我失去她后
After I lost her, I…
我失去了目标
I was nothing.
但和我一起的那些人
But the people I was with…
和他们在一起
being with them…
让我重拾了自我
I found myself.
另一个版本的我 更好的我
Some version of myself, a better self.
然而 总是感觉一切
Still, it always feels like it could just…
会再次一场空
just be swept away again.
但这不意味着那真的会发生
But that doesn't mean it will, and…
而且这不意味着
…and it doesn't mean.
即使那发生了 我不会再次重拾自我
that I couldn't find myself again if it does.
我
I, um…
我杀了他们
I killed them.
我杀了杀你哥哥的人
I killed the man who killed your brother.
是我杀的
I did.
我杀了他
I killed him.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不
No.
永远不要感到抱歉
Don't ever be sorry.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
见了鬼了
Holy hell.
就算掉进粪坑里 也没你看上去那么落魄
If shit could shit, it still wouldn't look as shitty as you.
上车
Get in.
尼根 我就知道
Negan. I knew it.
我就知道你还活着
I knew you were alive.
我当然活着
Hell yes, I am.
但你什么都不准说 知道吗
But you're not gonna say a word. You understand?
爸爸回家了 要来个惊喜
Daddy's home, ‭and it's gonna be a surprise.
该死 老子惊喜多得是
Hell, I got all sorts of surprises to roll out.
看起来你是对的
Well, looks like you're right.
正在运作
It's up and runnin'.
是的
Yep.
一桶桶弹壳 让尤金做千百发子弹
Buckets of casings for Eugene to turn into hundreds of bullets.
我们现在动手吧
Let's do it now.
不用毁坏机器
We don't take out the machines.
只用干掉头目
We take out the man.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你不用抱歉
You don't have to be.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.